SERGEI STAROV

Tukwila, WA • C: (702) 572-7335 • E: starovdev@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer in Test QA development professional with over 7 years of experience in software development, web, mobile automation and managing QA teams. Built and managed in-house QA team and off-shore QA team to deliver full range of testing across of all levels of test pyramid (from functional, UI, integration to unit tests)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, JavaScript, React, Java, HTML & CSS, Ruby, C/C++

Automation: Selenium WebDriver, Selenium Grid, Jenkins, TestNG, JUnit, Maven,

Appium, Gradle, Jasmine, Jest, Mocha, Sauce Labs, AWS, Cucumber,

Postman, Git

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TestPro, Sunnyvale, CA Software Automation Engineer

January 2020 – present

- Developed behavior-driven Test Automation framework for UI testing from scratch using Python, Selenium WebDriver, Jenkins, Sauce Labs
- Created test strategies and set up infrastructure test automation of web and mobile platforms.
- Owning of QA process, black, grey and white box testing methodologies
- Mentoring junior QA engineers.

Auto Club of Southern California (AAA), Los Angeles, CA February 2018 – January 2020 Software Engineer

- Developed applications for online insurance products exclude/remove/add drivers from auto insurance policy with React, Javascript, Typescript used by hundreds of thousands customers.
- Developed and maintained unit tests using Jasmine, Jest, Mocha frameworks following TDD practices and mock testing techniques
- Evaluated applications' code in compliance with OWASP security practices and eliminated vulnerabilities

Telit IoT Platforms, Boca Raton, FL Software Automation Lead

- Built QA team by leading the hiring, training process and managing both onsite and offshore teams
- Created automation test suites for UI and RESTful services using Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, TestRail and Java, automation solutions for CI/CD process with Jenkins, Maven, Selenium Grid, AWS. As a result, time to verify new builds/releases has been significantly reduced (up to 80%).
- Developed efficient and secure internal tool for back-end API testing (integration testing)
- Developed and maintained application for performance/load testing of company servers.

CreativeDrive, Hollywood, FL Software Automation Engineer

August 2015 – April 2016

- Created more than 300 automated scripts for testing CreativeDrive asset management release software using Selenium WebDriver, Java and JUnit
- Work with technical leads from development and DevOps on the overall test automation ecosystem across engineering practice with effective CI/CD strategies
- Worked closely with Dev, PM teams in an agile setting with two weeks sprint planning, retrospective and daily standups.

EDUCATION

BA in Legal Studies , Herzen State University, St. Petersburg, Russia	2014
Computer Science, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL	2017
Computer Programming, University of California Santa Cruz, Sunnyvale, CA	2020